Life is a Cabaret.
Cabaret is a music, drama, romance film directed by Bob Fosse.
Inside the Kit Kat Club of 1931 Berlin, starry-eyed singer Sally Bowles and an impish emcee sound the
clarion call to decadent fun, while outside a certain political party grows into a brutal force.
Sally Bowles, played by Liza Minnelli.
Brian Roberts, played by Michael York.
Maximilian von Heune, played by Helmut Griem.
Master of Ceremonies, played by Joel Grey.
Fritz Wendel, played by Fritz Wepper.
Natalia Landauer, played by Marisa Berenson.
Cabaret is a 1972 American musical drama film directed and
choreographed by Bob Fosse from a screenplay by Jay Presson Allen.
It is based on the 1966 stage musical by Joe Masteroff (book) and the duo Kander and Ebb (music), which in turn was based on
the 1951 play I Am a Camera by John Van Druten and the 1939 novel Goodbye to Berlin by Christopher Isherwood.
It stars Liza Minnelli, Michael York, Helmut
Griem, Marisa Berenson, and Joel Grey.
Multiple numbers from the stage score were used for the film, which also featured three
other songs by Kander and Ebb, including two written for the adaptation.
In the traditional manner of musical theater, most major characters in the stage version sing to express their emotions and advance the plot; in the film, however, the musical numbers are almost entirely diegetic and take place
inside the club, with the exception of "Tomorrow Belongs to Me", which is not performed in the club or by the club characters, but is still diegetic, a nationalistic song sung by a Nazi youth and the German crowd.
Cabaret was released in the United States on
February 13, 1972, by Allied Artists.
The film received critical acclaim and eventually earned more than $42 million
in the box office against a production budget of $4.6 million.
At the 45th Academy Awards, the film won in eight categories - including Best Director (Fosse), Best Actress (Minnelli), Best
Supporting Actor (Grey), and Best Score - holding the record for most Oscars earned by a film not honored for Best Picture.
In 1995, Cabaret was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United States National
Film Registry as being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, nazi,
entertainer, cabaret, bisexuality.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.